[{"id":"6494","question":"<p>The noise was (1)\/so faintly that (2)\/one had to strain (3)\/one&rsquo;s ears to hear it (4). No error (5).&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"1","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:26:27","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6539","question":"<p>In a certain code POACHED is written as BPQBEFI. How is COUNTER written in that code?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"VPDMSFU   ","option2":"VPDOSFU","option3":"VPDMUFS","option4":"DPVMSFU","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"VPDMSFU   ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:39:26","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>POACHED &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;COUNTER<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>BPQBEFI &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;VPDMSFU<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6517","question":"<p>Two-fifty of one number is equal to one-third of another number. What is the respective ratio of the first number to the second number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"6:5          ","option2":"7:8 ","option3":"5:6           ","option4":"8:7        ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"5:6           ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 09:26:34","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let one number is x and another number is y then,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;x&times;<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub> = y&times;<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>\/<sub>y <\/sub>= <sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub> = 5:6<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6504","question":"<p>What approximate value will come in place of question mark (?) in the following questions? (you are not expected to calculate the exact value.)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>29.8% of 260 + 60.01% of 510 &ndash; 103.57 = ?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"450 ","option2":"320","option3":"210","option4":"280 ","option5":"350","correct_option":"280 ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:48:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">? =&nbsp;<sup>260 &times; 30<\/sup>\/<sub>100&nbsp;<\/sub>+&nbsp;<sup>510 &times; 60<\/sup>\/<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;&ndash; 100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">&nbsp;78 + 306 &ndash; 100 284<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">Required answer = 280<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6489","question":"<p>(A) Asinine&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(B) Furious&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(C) Fortunate&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(D) Ridiculous<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A-D               ","option2":"A-B           ","option3":"A-C               ","option4":"B-C              ","option5":"B-D","correct_option":"A-D               ","qa_date":"2016-06-01 07:16:37","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li>Asinine __of or like an ass, idiotic<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Furious + angry, boiling, enraged, fierce, furring, gives, mad, railing, violent, stormy,<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Fortunate __ Advantageous, blessed, bright, lucky, happy, successful, felicitous, importunate<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Ridiculous __ absurd, comical, derisory, farcical, foolish, funny, stupid, ludicrous<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Hence, A-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6515","question":"<p>Find the average of the following set of scores.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 216,&nbsp; 463, 154,&nbsp; 605,&nbsp; 446,&nbsp; 336<\/p>\r\n","option1":"387 ","option2":"370","option3":"379","option4":"380","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"370","qa_date":"2016-06-02 09:18:41","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required average = <sup>addition of all six numbers<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = <sup>2220<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub> = 370.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6537","question":"<p>In a certain way code WEAK is written as 5%9$ and WHEN is written as 5*%7. How HANK is written in that code?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"*9$7       ","option2":"9*$7         ","option3":"$97*         ","option4":"9*7$        ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"None of these        ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:24:39","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>As WEAK ------ 5%9$<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; WHEN ------ 5*%7<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Then&nbsp; HANK ------- *97$.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; WHEN ------ 5*%7<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Then&nbsp; HANK ------- *97$.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6548","question":"<p>Which of the following combinations of employee-off day-shift day is <strong>not correct<\/strong>?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"T \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Thursday \u00e2\u20ac\u201c ll             ","option2":"V\u00e2\u20ac\u201c Friday \u00e2\u20ac\u201c lll             ","option3":"P  \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Wednesday \u00e2\u20ac\u201c l","option4":"Z \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Saturday \u00e2\u20ac\u201c l                ","option5":"All are correct","correct_option":"P  \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Wednesday \u00e2\u20ac\u201c l","qa_date":"2016-06-07 06:48:52","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>the combination P &ndash; Wednesday &ndash; l is not correct.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6536","question":"<p>A &lsquo;square&rsquo; is related to &lsquo;Cube&rsquo; in the same way as a &lsquo;Circle&rsquo; is related to<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Sphere ","option2":"Circumference ","option3":"Diameter ","option4":"Area   ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Sphere ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:24:39","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>As solid figure of the square in cube similarly solid figure of &lsquo;circle&rsquo; is &lsquo;sphere&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6529","question":"<p>Two gils and four boys are to be seated in row in such a way that the girls do not sit together. In how many different ways can it be done?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"720","option2":"480","option3":"360","option4":"240","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"480","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:49:55","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>4 boys can be seated in a row in&nbsp;<span style=\"font-size:14px\"><sup>4<\/sup><\/span>P<sub>4<\/sub>&nbsp;= 4! Ways<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Now in the 5 gaps 2 girls can be arranged in&nbsp;<sup>5<\/sup>P<sub>2<\/sub>ways.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Hence, the number of ways in which no two girls sit together<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">= 4! &times;&nbsp;<sup>5<\/sup>P<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;= 4&times;3&times;2&times;5&times;4 = 480<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6510","question":"<p>3&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;5&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;13 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;43&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;176 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;891 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;5353&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"5","option2":"13","option3":"43","option4":"176","option5":"891","correct_option":"176","qa_date":"2016-06-02 08:00:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">3 &times; 1 + 2 = 5<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">5 &times; 2 + 3 = 13<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">13 &times; 3 + 4 = 43<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">43 &times; 4 + 5 = 177 &ne; <strong>(176)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6477","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>:&nbsp; Choose the word which is <strong>most opposite<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>TERRIBLE<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Better   ","option2":"wonderful   ","option3":"extreme  ","option4":"awful ","option5":"fearful","correct_option":"wonderful   ","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:12:07","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>&lsquo;Wonderful &lsquo;in most opposite in meaning of the world &rsquo;terrible&rsquo; as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6544","question":"<p>How many such digits are there in the above sequence which are immediately preceded as well as followed by digits?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"None","option2":"One ","option3":"Two  ","option4":"Three  ","option5":"More than three ","correct_option":"None","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:57:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6514","question":"<p>The total number of students in a school is 7,064.If the number of girls in the school is 3,946 then what is the respective ratio of the total number of boys to the total number of girls in the school?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1559:1973         ","option2":"1981:1551         ","option3":"1973:1559          ","option4":"1551:1981       ","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"1559:1973         ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 09:16:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The total number of boys in the school = 7064 &ndash; 3946 = 3118.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Respective ratio of boys and girls = 3118:3946 = 1559:1973.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6480","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>FIRST <\/strong>after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"E","correct_option":"B","qa_date":"2016-06-01 06:53:23","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6519","question":"<p>Rs. 6,000 becomes Rs. 7,200 in 4 years at a certain rate of simple interest. If the rate becomes 1.5 times of itself, the amount of the same principle in 5 years will be&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 8,000","option2":"Rs. 8,250 ","option3":"Rs. 9,250    ","option4":"Rs. 9,000    ","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"Rs. 8,250 ","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:21:05","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>SI = Rs. (7200-6000) = Rs. 1200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>SI =&nbsp;<sup>PRT<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;= 1200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;R&times;4<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;=&nbsp;<sup>1200&times;100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>6000&times;4<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 5%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>New rate of R = 5&times;1.5 = 7.5%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Then, SI =&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;75&times;5<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=Rs. 2250<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Amount = Rs. (6000+2250)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;= Rs. 8250<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6522","question":"<p>A sum of money is divided among A, B, C and D in the ratio of 3: 5: 9 : 13 respectively. If the share of C is Rs. 2412 more than the share of A, then what is the total amount of money of B and D together? &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 4422  ","option2":"Rs. 7236    ","option3":"Rs. 6030    ","option4":"Rs. 4,824    ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"Rs. 7236    ","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:25:42","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>x = 3+5+9+13 = 30.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>C&#39;s share = Rs. 9x\/30 = 3x\/10<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>A&#39;s share = Rs. 3x\/30 = Rs. x\/10.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>According to the question,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><span style=\"font-size:14px\"><sup>3x\/<\/sup><sub>10<\/sub>&nbsp;-&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>\/<sub>10&nbsp;<\/sub><\/span>= 2412<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = 2412&times;5 = Rs. 12060<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Amount received by B and D together = [<span style=\"font-size:14px\">&nbsp;<sup>(5+13)<\/sup>\/<sub>30<\/sub><\/span>&times;12060]<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; = Rs. 7236.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6473","question":"<p>How did the author manage to call the clerk?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"By dragging the phone towards himself.        ","option2":"By hitting the button on the machine","option3":"By shouting for help         ","option4":"By flinging toast at the phone on the wall and then asking the clerk for help            ","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"By flinging toast at the phone on the wall and then asking the clerk for help            ","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:09:18","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The answer can easily inferred from the passage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6511","question":"<p>6 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;7&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;16 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;41&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;90&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;154&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;292&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7","option2":"16","option3":"41","option4":"90","option5":"154","correct_option":"90","qa_date":"2016-06-02 08:00:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">6 + 1<sup>2<\/sup> = 6 + 1 = 7<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">7 + 3<sup>2<\/sup> = 7+ 9 = 16<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">16 + 5<sup>2<\/sup> = 16 + 25 = 41<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">41 + 7<sup>2<\/sup> = 41 + 49 = 90<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>90 + 9<sup>2<\/sup> = 90 + 81 = 171&nbsp; &ne; <strong>(154)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>171+11<sup>2<\/sup> = 171 + 121 = 292<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6527","question":"<p>Shilpa spent 8% on school fees, 25% on rent and 17% on furniture. 25% of the remaining amount was spent on medical bills and the remaining Rs. 6,000 was set aside for investment. How much money she spent on rent?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 3,750","option2":"Rs. 6,000","option3":"Rs. 4,000","option4":"Rs. 3,250","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Rs. 4,000","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:43:31","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Income of Shilpa = Rs. x let<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Expenditure on school fees, rent and furniture&nbsp;= ( 8 + 25 + 17)% = 50%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Remaining Rs.&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Expenditure on medical bills =&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;&times;&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4<\/sub>&nbsp;= Rs.&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Remaining amount =&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;-&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;=&nbsp;<sup>4x - x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;= Rs.&nbsp;<sup>3x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So,&nbsp;<sup>3x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8<\/sub>&nbsp;= 6000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&rarr; x =&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;8<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;= Rs. 4000<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6528","question":"<p>A boat running downstream cover a distance of 16 km in 2 hours while for covering the same distance upstream it takes 4 hours. What is the speed of the boat in still water?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"4 kmph","option2":"6 kmph","option3":"8 kmph","option4":"Data inadequate  ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"6 kmph","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:46:56","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Rate upstream&nbsp;=&nbsp;<sup>16<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;kmph<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; = 8 kmph<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Rate downstream =&nbsp;<sup>16<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sub>&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/sub>&nbsp;= 4 kmph<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Rate in still water =&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>(8+4) kmph<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; = 6 kmph<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6487","question":"<p>(A) Notion &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(B) Symbol&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(C) Concept &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; (D) message<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A - B ","option2":"B - C ","option3":"A - C","option4":"C - D","option5":"B - D ","correct_option":"B - D ","qa_date":"2016-06-01 07:16:37","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li>Notion __ apprehension, belief, concept, fancy, image, judgment, knowledge<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Symbol __ badge, emblem, image, loge, re3presentation sign, token, type<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Concept __ abstraction conception, construct, idea, image, type, view<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Massage __ rubbing, kneading, kneading, manipulation, rap __down<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Hence, B-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6521","question":"<p>Ashok started a business investing Rs. 25000. After 3 months Vinod &nbsp;joined him with a capital of Rs. 30000. At the end of the year, make a profit of Rs. 19000. What will be Ashok&#39;s&nbsp;share?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 5000","option2":"Rs. 10000","option3":"Rs. 9000  ","option4":"Rs. 8000    ","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"Rs. 10000","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:23:17","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Equivalent capitals for one month are<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Rs. 2500&times;12 = Rs. 300000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Rs. 3000&times;9 = Rs. 270000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Profit is to be divided in the ratio 300000:270000 i.e. 10:9<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Sum of the ratios = 10+9 = 19<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Ashok&rsquo;s share&nbsp;Rs.&nbsp;<sup>10<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>19<\/sub>&nbsp;&times; 19000&nbsp;= Rs. 10000.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6538","question":"<p>Four of the following five are alike in a certain way and so form a group. Which is the one that does not belong to that group?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Diabetes ","option2":"Smallpox ","option3":"Conjunctivitis  ","option4":"Chickenpox ","option5":"Plague","correct_option":"Diabetes ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:26:57","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>All the rest are infectious diseases.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6516","question":"<p>If the fractions <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>,<sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>,<sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13<\/sub>,<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub> and <sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub> are arranged&nbsp; in ascending&nbsp; order of their values ,which one will be the fourth?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7\/11      ","option2":"3\/5      ","option3":"11\/13         ","option4":"8\/9      ","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"11\/13         ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 09:22:42","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5 <\/sub>= 0.60,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7 <\/sub>= 0.71<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13 <\/sub>= 0.85<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11 <\/sub>= 0.64<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>9 <\/sub>= 0.89<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>The ascending order of the fractions <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>, <sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11, <\/sub><sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7, <\/sub><sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13, <\/sub><sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>9.<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Fourth in order = <sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13.<\/sub><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6524","question":"<p>What is the cost of painting a hall whose area is 729 sq. metres if the rate of painting per square meter is Rs. 28?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 3,042","option2":"Rs. 3,758","option3":"Rs. 3,024","option4":"Cannot be determine.","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"Cannot be determine.","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:38:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Cannot be determined.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6530","question":"<p>Average weight of three boys P, T and R is 54<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;kgs while the average weight of three boys T, F and G is 53 kgs. What is the average weight of P,T, R, F and H?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"53.8 kgs","option2":"52.4 kgs","option3":"53.2 kgs","option4":"Data inadequate ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Data inadequate ","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:52:04","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>We are to determine the average weight of P,T,R, H F and H. Obviously, this cannot be determined as we don&rsquo;t know the weight of H.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6478","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most opposite<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>RUDIMENTARY<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Advanced    ","option2":"basic","option3":"evil","option4":"forward","option5":"artificial","correct_option":"Advanced    ","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:12:41","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>&lsquo;Advanced&rsquo; is most opposite in meaning of the world &lsquo;rudimentary &lsquo;as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6547","question":"<p>On which day of the week does Q have off day?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Wednesday ","option2":"Thursday","option3":"Tuesday","option4":"Saturday ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Tuesday","qa_date":"2016-06-07 06:48:52","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Q has off day on Tuesday.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6482","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>SIXTH (LAST) <\/strong>after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"E","option5":"F","correct_option":"C","qa_date":"2016-06-01 06:53:23","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6498","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word from the given options.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"demand ","option2":"ensure ","option3":"consider ","option4":"regulate","option5":"encompass","correct_option":"ensure ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:35:31","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6576","question":"<p><strong>Statement :&nbsp;<\/strong>All chairs are keys.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; All keys are balloons.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Some balloons are mirrors.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Some mirrors are desks.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions: &nbsp; &nbsp;I.<\/strong>Some desks are keys.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\"><strong>II.<\/strong>Some balloons are chairs.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\"><strong>III.<\/strong>Some mirrors are balloons.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Only I follows","option2":"Only II follows","option3":"Only III follows","option4":"Only II and III follow","option5":"All I, II and III follow","correct_option":"Only II and III follow","qa_date":"2016-06-08 06:01:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>All chairs are keys.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>All keys are ballons.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>A + A ---- A<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>All chairs are ballons.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6503","question":"<p><strong>Directions:&nbsp;<\/strong>What approximate value will come in place of question mark (?) in the following questions? (you are not expected to calculate the exact value.)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>9228.789 &ndash; 5021.832 + 1496.989 = ?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"6500 ","option2":"6000","option3":"6300","option4":"5700","option5":"5100","correct_option":"5700","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:42:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">? &nbsp;9230 &ndash; 5022 + 1500 &nbsp;5708<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">Required answer = 5700&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6561","question":"<p>Four of the following five are alike inn a certain way based on their positions in the above arrangement and so form a group.&nbsp; Which of the following does not belong to the group?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"CG","option2":"GE","option3":"GH","option4":"DE","option5":"FD","correct_option":"GE","qa_date":"2016-06-07 08:13:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Except in GE, in all others there is only one person between the two.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6475","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most similar<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>FLINGING<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Touching ","option2":"holding ","option3":"bending ","option4":"feeling ","option5":"throwing  ","correct_option":"throwing  ","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:10:39","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In the passage &lsquo;flinging&rsquo; means &lsquo;throwing&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6579","question":"<p><strong>Statements :<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;All doors are windows.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;No window is house.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Some houses are buildings.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;All buildings are skies<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions &nbsp;&nbsp;I.<\/strong>Some skies are doors.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\"><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; II.<\/strong>Some skies are houses.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\"><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; III.<\/strong>Some buildings are skies<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Only I follow","option2":"Only II follow","option3":"Only III follow","option4":"Only II and III follow","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Only II follow","qa_date":"2016-06-08 06:01:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>All doors are windows.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>No window is house.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>A+E ---- E<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>No door is house.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Some houses are buildings.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>All buildings are skies.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>I+A ------ I<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>some houses are skies.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6571","question":"<p>What is the respective ratio between the number of boys in school-C, number of girls in School-B and total number of students in School-E?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"45 : 7 : 97    ","option2":"43 : 9 : 97   ","option3":"45 : 7 : 87   ","option4":"43 : 9 : 87       ","option5":"","correct_option":"45 : 7 : 97    ","qa_date":"2016-06-08 05:51:17","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of girls in school-B<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;9<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;- 40<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 540 &ndash; 400 = 140<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Number of Students in School-E<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;29<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;= 1740<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required ratio = 900: 140: 1740 = 45: 7: 87<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6470","question":"<p>What was the author making?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"He was making a toaster which could talk.","option2":"He was making a machine which could control animal behavior.","option3":"He was making a machine which could convert itself into toaster.","option4":"He was making a machine which could exchange the minds of two entities.","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"He was making a machine which could exchange the minds of two entities.","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:07:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Refer to the second half of the second paragraph.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6506","question":"<p>What approximate value will come in place of the question mark (?) in the following questions? (You are not expected to calculate the exact value.)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>150<\/sup>\/<sub>17<\/sub>&nbsp;&times;&nbsp;<sup>199<\/sup>\/<sub>13<\/sub>&nbsp;&divide;&nbsp;<sup>16<\/sup>\/<sub>91<\/sub>&nbsp;= ?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"650","option2":"700","option3":"770","option4":"820","option5":"850","correct_option":"770","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:48:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">? =&nbsp;<sup>150<\/sup>\/<sub>17<\/sub>&nbsp;&times;&nbsp;<sup>199<\/sup>\/<sub>13<\/sub>&nbsp;&divide;&nbsp;<sup>16<\/sup>\/<sub>91<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">&nbsp;<sup>150<\/sup>\/<sub>17<\/sub>&nbsp;&times;&nbsp;<sup>200<\/sup>\/<sub>16&nbsp;<\/sub>&nbsp;= 770&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6559","question":"<p>Which of the following pairs represents the people standing at the extreme ends of the line?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"FH","option2":"CE","option3":"DE","option4":"CH","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"CE","qa_date":"2016-06-07 08:13:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>C and E are standing at the extreme ends of the line.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6556","question":"<p><strong>Statements: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>H&nbsp; @&nbsp; V,&nbsp; V&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; M,&nbsp; M&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; R<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;I<\/strong>. R&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; H<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;II<\/strong>. H&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; R<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"1","qa_date":"2016-06-07 07:38:34","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Statements:&nbsp;<\/strong>H&nbsp; @&nbsp; V,&nbsp; V&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; M,&nbsp; M&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; R<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>After&nbsp; conversion <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>H&nbsp; &le;&nbsp; V,&nbsp; V&nbsp; =&nbsp; M,&nbsp; M&nbsp; &gt;&nbsp; R<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Or,&nbsp; H &nbsp;&le;&nbsp; V&nbsp; =&nbsp; M&nbsp; &gt;&nbsp; R<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-roman\">\r\n\t<li>R&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; H&nbsp; &rarr;&nbsp; R&nbsp; &gt;&nbsp; H&nbsp; :Not&nbsp; true<\/li>\r\n\t<li>H &times; R&nbsp; &rarr;&nbsp; H &gt; R :&nbsp; not true<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.5in\">If we consider H = V, then H &gt; R<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.5in\">But H may be smaller than V and R is also smaller than V.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6578","question":"<p><strong>Statement :<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;Some boxes are toys.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Some toys are nails.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Some nails are stores.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Some stores are shops.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions: &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;I.<\/strong>Some shops are toys.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\"><strong>II.<\/strong>Some nails are boxes<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\"><strong>III.<\/strong>No Shop is toy.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Only I follows","option2":"Only III follows","option3":"Only either I or III follows","option4":"Only II follows","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Only either I or III follows","qa_date":"2016-06-08 06:01:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>All the four Premises are particular Affirmative (I-type).<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Therefore only either conclusion I or III follows.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6568","question":"<p><strong>Step III of an input is:&nbsp;<\/strong>27 tube 34 gas chamber row 74 53<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Which of the following steps will be the last but one?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"VI","option2":"VII","option3":"VIII","option4":"V","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"V","qa_date":"2016-06-07 10:20:00","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Step III<\/strong>: 27 tube 34 gas chamber row 74 53<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step IV<\/strong>: 27 tube 34 row gas chamber 74 53<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step V<\/strong>: 27 tube 34 row 53 gas chamber 74<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step VI<\/strong>: 27 tube 34 row 53 gas 74 chamber &nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6493","question":"<p>As they watched (1)\/the football match (2)\/the huge crowed (3)\/chant in unison (4). No error (5).&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"1","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:26:27","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In place of&nbsp;As they watched, &nbsp;&nbsp;As they&nbsp;attending should be used.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6577","question":"<p><strong>Statements :&nbsp;<\/strong>Some drums are posters,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;All posters are windows.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Some windows are tablets.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;All tablets are books.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusion: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;I.<\/strong>Some windows are drums.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\"><strong>II.<\/strong>Some books are poster.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\"><strong>III.<\/strong>Some tablets are drums<\/p>\r\n","option1":"None follow","option2":"Only I follows","option3":"Only II follows","option4":"Only III follows","option5":"Only I and II follow","correct_option":"Only I follows","qa_date":"2016-06-08 06:01:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Some drums are posters.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>All posters are windows.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>I+A------ I<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, &#39;some drums are windows.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6580","question":"<p><strong>Statements:<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;All rivers are walls.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; All walls are stones.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;All stones are clothes.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; All clothes are trees.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;I. &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>Some trees are stones.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;II.<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Some clothes are rivers.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; III<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;All walls are clothes.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Only I and II follow","option2":"Only I and III follow","option3":"Only II and III follow","option4":"All I, II and III follow","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"All I, II and III follow","qa_date":"2016-06-08 06:01:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>All rivers are walls.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>All walls are stones.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>A+A ------ A<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>All rivers are stones.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Same condition implicites for all conclusions.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6574","question":"<p>Number of Girls School-A is&nbsp;<strong>approximately<\/strong>&nbsp;what percent of total number of students in School-B?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"55","option2":"50","option3":"32","option4":"41","option5":"45","correct_option":"41","qa_date":"2016-06-07 17:22:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of girls in School-A<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;12<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;- 500<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 720 &ndash; 500 = 220<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required percentage<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>220<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>540<\/sub>&times;100 &asymp; 41<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6501","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word from the given options.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"stimulated","option2":"calculated  ","option3":"considered  ","option4":"hastened","option5":"designed","correct_option":"considered  ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:35:31","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6509","question":"<p>484 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;240 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;120 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;57&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 26.5&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;11.25&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;3.625&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"240 ","option2":"120","option3":"57","option4":"26.5","option5":"11.25","correct_option":"120","qa_date":"2016-06-02 08:00:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">(484 &divide; 2) &ndash; 2 = 242 &ndash; 2 = 240<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">(240 &divide; 2) &ndash; 2 = 120 &ndash; 2 = 118 &ne; <strong>(120)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">(118&divide; 2) &ndash; 2 = 59 &ndash; 2 = 57<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(57&divide;2) &ndash; 2 = 28.5 &ndash; 2 = 26.5<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6476","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most similar<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>INITIATED<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Withstand  ","option2":"worked  ","option3":"stopped ","option4":"started","option5":"culminate","correct_option":"started","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:11:23","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In the passage &lsquo;initiated&rsquo; means &lsquo;started&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6505","question":"<p>What approximate value will come in place of question mark (?) in the following questions? (you are not expected to calculate the exact value.)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1299 &divide; 19.99 &times; 25.01 + 400.01 =?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"2025","option2":"2300","option3":"1925","option4":"2200","option5":"1700","correct_option":"2025","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:48:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">? =&nbsp;<sup>1300<\/sup>\/<sub>20&nbsp;<\/sub>&times; 25 + 400<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1in\">&nbsp;1625 + 400 = 2025&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6534","question":"<p>How many such pairs of letters are there in the word, UNWANTED, each of which has as many letters between its two letters as there are between them in the English alphabets?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"None ","option2":"One","option3":"Two ","option4":"Three  ","option5":"More than three","correct_option":"Three  ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:18:26","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>U&nbsp; N&nbsp; W&nbsp; A&nbsp; N&nbsp; T&nbsp; E&nbsp; D<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>In forward direction (U,W).<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>In backward direction (D,E) , (T,W).<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6520","question":"<p>The price of a certain item is increased by 15% If a consumer wants to keep his expenditure on the item the same as before, how much percent must he reduce his consumption of that item?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"15%  ","option2":"16<sup>2<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>3<\/sub>%","option3":"10<sup>20<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>23<\/sub>%","option4":"13<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>23<\/sub>%   ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"13<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>23<\/sub>%   ","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:21:05","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>If the price of the commodity increase by R% &nbsp;then reduction in consumption, not to increase the expenditure is&nbsp;(<sup>R<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100+R<\/sub>&times;100%)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>15<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>(100+15)<\/sub>&times;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>15<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>115<\/sub>&times;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>300<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>23<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 13<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>23<\/sub>&nbsp;%<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6532","question":"<p>Nandhini bought 20 pens, 8 packets of wax colours, 6 calculayors and 7 pencil boxes . The price of one pen is Rs. 7 , one packet of wax colour is Rs. 22, one calculator is Rs. 175 and one pencil box is 14 more than the combine price of one pen and one packet of wax colours. How much amount did Nandhini&nbsp;pay to the shopkeeper?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 1,381   ","option2":"Rs. 1, 815  ","option3":"Rs. 1,667     ","option4":"Rs.1,572     ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Rs. 1,667     ","qa_date":"2016-06-06 08:00:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>C.P. of one pencil box<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 7 + 22 + 14 = Rs. 43<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Total amount paid by Harshita<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. (20 &times; 7 + 8 &times; 22 + 6 &times; 175 + 7 &times; 43)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. (140 + 176 + 1050 + 301)&nbsp; = Rs. 1667<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6490","question":"<p>(A) Companion &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (B) Amateur&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(C) Adept &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(D) Adherent<\/p>\r\n","option1":"B-C              ","option2":"B-D               ","option3":"C-D              ","option4":"A-B             ","option5":"A-D","correct_option":"A-D","qa_date":"2016-06-01 07:16:37","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li>Companion __ accomplice, aide, ally, assistant, associate fellow, mate, partner<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Amateur - buff, dabbler, dilettante, &nbsp;ham, layman, non-professional,<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Adept __ able, accomplished, adroit, versed, skilled, proficient, practiced nimble.<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Adherent __ admirer, advocate, devotee, disciple, fan, follower, supporter<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Hence, A-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6507","question":"<p>2<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8&nbsp;<\/sub>- 1<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>6<\/sub>&nbsp;= ? + 1<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>32<\/sub>&nbsp;- 1<sup>9<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>64. &nbsp;What will come in ?<\/sub><\/p>\r\n","option1":"2<sup>9<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<\/sub>32 <sub>  ","option2":"1<sup>9<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<\/sub>64<sub>","option3":"2<sup>5<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<\/sub>32 <sub>      ","option4":"1<sup>11<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<\/sub>64 <sub>","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"1<sup>11<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<\/sub>64 <sub>","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:52:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>? = 2 &ndash; 1 &ndash; 1 + 1 +<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8 -&nbsp;<\/sub><sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>16-&nbsp;<\/sub><sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>32<\/sub>&nbsp;-&nbsp;<sup>9<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>64)&nbsp;<\/sub>= 1+&nbsp;<sup>8-4-2+9<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>64&nbsp;<\/sub>= 1 +&nbsp;<sup>11<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>64<\/sub>&nbsp;= 1<sup>11<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>64<\/sub><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6558","question":"<p>What is the position of G with respect to E?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Immediate left ","option2":"Second to the left ","option3":"Third  to the left ","option4":"Third  to the right","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Third  to the left ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 08:13:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>G is third to the left of E.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6495","question":"<p>A vast number (1)\/of people greeted (2)\/the film star on his arrival (3)\/at the airport (4). No error (5).&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"3","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:26:27","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6564","question":"<p><strong>Step III of an Input:<\/strong>&nbsp;15 window 29 93 86 sail tower buy&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Which of the following will be&nbsp;<strong>step VI<\/strong>?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"15 window 29 tower 86 sail 93 buy ","option2":"15 window 29 tower 86 93 sail buy ","option3":"15 window 29 tower 93 86 sail buy  ","option4":"There will be no such step. ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"15 window 29 tower 86 sail 93 buy ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 10:20:00","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Step III<\/strong>: 15 window 29 93 86 sail tower buy<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step IV<\/strong>: window 29 tower 93 86 sail buy<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step V<\/strong>: 15 window 29 tower 86 93 sail buy<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step VI<\/strong>: 15 window 29 tower 86 sail 93 buy<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Eventually, step IV is the last step.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6474","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most similar<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>SYNTHETIC<\/strong><\/p>\r\n","option1":"Loud","option2":"clothed","option3":"real ","option4":"electron","option5":"soft","correct_option":"clothed","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:10:08","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In the passage &lsquo;synthetic &lsquo;means &lsquo;clothed&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6492","question":"<p>Sugar-sweetened drinks does not(1)\/ pose any particular health risk, and \/ (2)are not a unique risk factor \/ (3) for obesity or heart disease. (4) No error&nbsp; (5).<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"5","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:26:27","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6472","question":"<p>Who does the term &lsquo;the brute&rsquo; used in the passage refer to?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"The author          ","option2":"The toaster          ","option3":"The machine        ","option4":"The clerk        ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"The clerk        ","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:08:32","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Refer to the second half of the third paragraph.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6553","question":"<p><strong>Statements: &nbsp;<\/strong>K&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; B,&nbsp; B&nbsp; @&nbsp; D,&nbsp; D&nbsp; #&nbsp; K<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;I<\/strong>. B&nbsp; @&nbsp; K<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;II<\/strong>. B #&nbsp; K<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"2","qa_date":"2016-06-07 07:38:34","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Statements: &nbsp;<\/strong>K&nbsp; &times; B, B&nbsp; @&nbsp; D,&nbsp; D&nbsp; #&nbsp; K<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>After&nbsp; conversion <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>K&nbsp; &gt; B,&nbsp; B&nbsp; &le;&nbsp; D,&nbsp; D&nbsp; &lt;&nbsp; K<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Or,&nbsp; B&nbsp; &le;&nbsp; D&nbsp; &lt;&nbsp; K<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-roman\">\r\n\t<li>B&nbsp; @&nbsp; K &rarr;&nbsp; B&nbsp; &le;&nbsp; K&nbsp; : Not&nbsp; true&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; K is definitely greater than B.<\/li>\r\n\t<li>B&nbsp; #&nbsp; K &rarr;&nbsp; B&nbsp; &lt;&nbsp; K : true<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n"},{"id":"6565","question":"<p><strong>Input:&nbsp;<\/strong>Station hurry 39 67 all men 85 59<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>How many steps will be required to complete the rearrangement?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Four","option2":"five   ","option3":"Six","option4":"Three","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"five   ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 10:20:00","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Input<\/strong>: Station hurry 39 67 all men 86 59<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step I<\/strong>: 39 station hurry 67 all men 86 59<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step II<\/strong>: 39 station 59 hurry 67 all men 86<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step III<\/strong>: 39 station 59 men&nbsp; hurry 67 all 86<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step IV<\/strong>: 39 station 59 men 67 hurry all 86<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step V<\/strong>: 39 station 59 men 67 hurry 86 all&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6535","question":"<p>If the letters in the word &lsquo;AMONGST&rsquo; are arranged in the English alphabetical order, the position of how many letters will remain unchanged?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"None  ","option2":"One ","option3":"Two  ","option4":"Three ","option5":"More than three ","correct_option":"More than three ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:24:39","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>A <\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;M&nbsp;&nbsp; O&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>N<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; G&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>S <\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>T<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>A <\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;G&nbsp;&nbsp; M&nbsp; <strong>&nbsp;N<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; O&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>S<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>T<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6513","question":"<p>4&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;2.5&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;3.5 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;6.5 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;15.5&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;41.25&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;126.75&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"2.5","option2":"3.5","option3":"6.5","option4":"15.5","option5":"41.25 ","correct_option":"6.5","qa_date":"2016-06-02 08:00:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">4 &times; 0.5 + 0.5 = 2 + 0.5 = 2.5<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">2.5 &times; 1 + 1 = 3.5<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">3.5 &times; 1.5 + 1.5 = 6.75 &ne; <strong>(6.5)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">6.75 &times; 2 + 2 = 15.5<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">15.5 &times; 2.5 + 2.5 = 38.75 + 2.5 = 41.25<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">41.25 &times; 3 + 3 = 123.75 + 3 = 126.75<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6481","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>THIRD <\/strong>after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"E","option3":"D","option4":"F","option5":"C","correct_option":"A","qa_date":"2016-06-01 06:53:23","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6542","question":"<p>Which of the following is exactly in the midway between the eleventh from the left end and the 7<sup>th<\/sup> from the right end?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"P","option2":"@","option3":"T","option4":"U","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"@","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:57:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>11<sup>th<\/sup> from left end &rarr; I<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>7<sup>th<\/sup> from right end &rarr;1<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Remaining element between I and 1 : @<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6488","question":"<p>(A) Limpid&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(B) Luscious<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(C) Acrid &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(D) Benign<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A-B","option2":"B-C","option3":"C-D ","option4":"B-D ","option5":"A-C","correct_option":"B-C","qa_date":"2016-06-01 07:16:37","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li>Limpid __ bright, bright, clear, comprehensible, crystal-clear, glassy, intelligible, pure<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Luscious__ appetizing, delicious, desirable, juicy, savory, sweet, tasty<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Acrid__ acid, acrimonious, bitter, sharp, burning, pungent, sarcastic<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Benign __ amiable, benevolent, friendly, genial, gentle, good, gracious<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Hence, B-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6572","question":"<p>What is the difference between the total number of students in School-F and the number of boys in School-E?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"820","option2":"860 ","option3":"880","option4":"900","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"None of these        ","qa_date":"2016-06-08 05:51:17","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required difference<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 1200 -&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;6<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 1200 &ndash; 36 = 840<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6570","question":"<p>What is the total number of girls in School-C, number of girls in school E and the number of boys in School-D together?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1700","option2":"1900","option3":"1600","option4":"1800","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"1800","qa_date":"2016-06-08 05:51:17","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of girls:<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>School C<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;26<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;- 90<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 1560 &ndash; 900 = 660<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>School E<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;29<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;- 1200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 1740 &ndash; 1200 = 540<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required answer<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 660 + 540 + 600 = 1800<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6566","question":"<p><strong>Step II of an input is:&nbsp;<\/strong>49 zone car battery 56 87 71 down<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Which of the following is defined definitely the input?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"car 49 battery zone 56 87 71 down ","option2":"zone 49 car battery 56 87 71 down ","option3":"battery car 49 zone 56 87 71 down  ","option4":"Cannot be determined  ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"car 49 battery zone 56 87 71 down ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 10:20:00","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>It is not possible to determine the Input from any given step.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6502","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word from the given options.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"twist ","option2":"stopped   ","option3":"mended","option4":"broken  ","option5":"abated","correct_option":"broken  ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:35:31","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6486","question":"<p>(A) Proximate &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(B) Elevated&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(C) Nimble&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;(D) Agile<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A-B","option2":"B-C","option3":"A-C","option4":"B-D","option5":"C-D","correct_option":"C-D","qa_date":"2016-06-01 07:16:37","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>(A) Proximate __ nearest or next, without anything between a cause and its effect.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(B)&nbsp; Elevated __ dignified, elated, grand, high, lofty. Noble, raised, sublime<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(C)&nbsp; Nimble __ active, agile, alert, brisk, deft, light-fitted, lively, ready<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(D) Agile __ active, adroit, brisk, clever, quick, sharp, swift, spry<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Hence, C-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6484","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>FIFTH<\/strong> after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"D","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"E","option5":"F","correct_option":"F","qa_date":"2016-06-01 06:53:23","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6573","question":"<p>In which school the total number of students (both boys and girls) together are equal to the number of girls in School-E?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"F","correct_option":"B","qa_date":"2016-06-08 05:51:17","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of students in School B<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>6000&times;9<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;= 540<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6543","question":"<p>Which of the following is the sixth to the right of the twentieth from the right end?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"5","option2":"F","option3":"P","option4":"K","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"P","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:57:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>6<sup>th<\/sup> to the right of 20<sup>th<\/sup> from the right end means<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>20-6=14<sup>th<\/sup> from the right end. There are altogether 27 elements in the above sequence and thee middle term, i.e. 14<sup>th<\/sup> element from either end is P. therefore, our required is &#39;P&#39;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6471","question":"<p>Why was the author two feet shorter when he woke up?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Because he was transformed into a duck.","option2":"Because the cat had jumped on him.","option3":"Because he was transformed into a telephone.","option4":"Because he had not made the machine correctly.","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"None of these       ","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:07:48","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Refer to the first half of the fourth paragraph.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6554","question":"<p><strong>Statements: &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>N&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; R,&nbsp; R&nbsp; @&nbsp; M,&nbsp; M&nbsp; $&nbsp; J<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I<\/strong>. N&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; M<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;II<\/strong>. N&nbsp; #&nbsp; M<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"3","qa_date":"2016-06-07 07:38:34","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Statements:&nbsp;<\/strong>N&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; R,&nbsp; R&nbsp; @&nbsp; M,&nbsp; M&nbsp; $&nbsp; J<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>After&nbsp; conversion <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>N&nbsp; =&nbsp; R,&nbsp; R&nbsp; &le;&nbsp; M,&nbsp; M&nbsp; &ge;&nbsp; J<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Or,&nbsp; N =&nbsp; R&nbsp; &le; M&nbsp; &ge;&nbsp; J<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-roman\">\r\n\t<li>N&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; M&nbsp; &rarr;&nbsp; N = M&nbsp; :&nbsp; not true<\/li>\r\n\t<li>N&nbsp; #&nbsp; M&nbsp; &rarr;&nbsp; N&nbsp; &lt;&nbsp; M :&nbsp; not true<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n"},{"id":"6567","question":"<p><strong>Input:&nbsp;<\/strong>news 79 53 glory for 46 29 task<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Which of the following will be step IV?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"29 task 46 news 53 glory 79 for ","option2":"29 task 46 news 53 79 glory for ","option3":"29 task 46 news 79 53 glory for ","option4":"29 news 79 53 glory for 46 task ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"29 task 46 news 53 79 glory for ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 10:20:00","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Input<\/strong>: news 79 53 glory for 46 29 task<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step I<\/strong>: 29 news 79 53 glory for 46 task<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step II<\/strong>: 29 task mews 79 53 glory for 46<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step III<\/strong>: 29 task 46&nbsp;news 79 53 glory for<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Step IV<\/strong>: 29 task 46&nbsp;news 53 79 glory for&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6555","question":"<p><strong>Statements: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>Z&nbsp; $&nbsp; K,&nbsp; K&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; T,&nbsp; T&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; F<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I<\/strong>. F&nbsp; #&nbsp; Z<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; II<\/strong>. Z&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; T<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"5","qa_date":"2016-06-07 07:38:34","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Statements: &nbsp;<\/strong>Z&nbsp; $&nbsp; K,&nbsp; K&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; T,&nbsp; T&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; F<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>After&nbsp; conversion <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Z&nbsp; &ge;&nbsp; K,&nbsp; K &gt; T ,&nbsp; T&nbsp; =&nbsp; F<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Or,&nbsp; Z&nbsp; &ge;&nbsp; K &gt;&nbsp; T&nbsp; =&nbsp; F<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-roman\">\r\n\t<li>F&nbsp; #&nbsp; Z &rarr; F&nbsp; &lt;&nbsp; Z&nbsp; :&nbsp; true<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Z&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; T&nbsp; &rarr;&nbsp; Z&nbsp; &gt;&nbsp; T&nbsp; :&nbsp; true<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n"},{"id":"6523","question":"<p>A person who spends 66<sup>2<\/sup>&frasl;3<span style=\"font-size:16px\"><sub>% of his income is able to save Rs. 1,200 per month. His monthly expenses (in Rs ) is:<\/sub><\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"1,200 ","option2":"2,400  ","option3":"3000  ","option4":"3200  ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"None of these       ","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:28:03","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>66<sup>2<\/sup>&frasl;3<span style=\"font-size:16px\"><sub>%&nbsp;<\/sub><\/span>&nbsp;of his income is 12000.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>33<sup><span style=\"font-size:10.8333px\">1<\/span><\/sup>&frasl;3<span style=\"font-size:16px\"><sub>% of his income = 6000.<\/sub><\/span><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><span style=\"font-size:16px\"><sub>He spent 6000 on expenses.<\/sub><\/span><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6549","question":"<p>Who among them has off day immediately on the next of V&rsquo;s off day?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"P","option2":"Z","option3":"T","option4":"Data inadequate","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Z","qa_date":"2016-06-07 06:48:52","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Z has off day immediately on the next day of V&rsquo;s off day.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6500","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word from the given options.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Presently ","option2":"Same","option3":"So   ","option4":"Like","option5":"Just","correct_option":"Just","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:35:31","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6526","question":"<p>Anil invested an amount for three years at a simple interest rate of 9 p.c.p.a. He got an amount of Rs. 19,050 at the end of three years. Which principal amount did he invest?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 14,500","option2":"Rs. 11,050","option3":"Rs. 15,000","option4":"Rs. 10,950","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Rs. 15,000","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:40:18","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let the principal be x<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Interest = (19050 &ndash; x)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Now ,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Principal =&nbsp;<sup>Interest&times;100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>Time &times; Rate<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= x =&nbsp;<sup>(19050 - x)&times; 100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>3&times;9<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 27x = 1905000 &ndash; 100x<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 127x = 1905000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&rarr; x =&nbsp;<sup>1905000<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>127<\/sub>&nbsp;= Rs. 15000<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6496","question":"<p>The weather is (1)\/much more warmer (2)\/than it was (3) \/a few days ago (4). No error (5).&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"4","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:26:27","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6512","question":"<p>5 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;7 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;16&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;57&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;277 &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;1245&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;7506&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7","option2":"16","option3":"57","option4":"244","option5":"1245","correct_option":"7","qa_date":"2016-06-02 08:00:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">5 &times; 1 + 1<sup>2<\/sup> = 6 &ne; <strong>(7)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">6 &times; 2 + 2<sup>2<\/sup> = 16<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">16 &times; 3 + 3<sup>2<\/sup> = 57<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">57 &times; 4 + 4<sup>2<\/sup> = 228 + 16 = 244<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 244&times;5 + 5<sup>2<\/sup> = 1220 + 25 = 1245<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6469","question":"<p>Which of the following is not true in the context of the passage?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"The clerk was part of the experiment right from the start ","option2":"The clerk managed to bring the author back to his original state.","option3":"The experiment did not go completely as planned.","option4":"The author\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s mind was transferred into the toaster.","option5":"All of the above are true.    ","correct_option":"The clerk was part of the experiment right from the start ","qa_date":"2016-05-31 18:06:39","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The answer can be easily inferred from the passage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6483","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>SECOND <\/strong>after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"E","option5":"F","correct_option":"E","qa_date":"2016-06-01 06:53:23","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6541","question":"<p>What should come in place of the question mark (?) in the following sequence?<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>5 E S,&nbsp; MIP,&nbsp; ?,&nbsp; 1 H Q<\/p>\r\n","option1":"T U A              ","option2":"T U 7           ","option3":"@ 91              ","option4":"T 9 1        ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"T U 7           ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 05:57:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>5----(+6) ----M -----(+6) ------ T&nbsp; -----(+6) ------ 1<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>E-----(+6) -----J -----(+6) ------ U&nbsp; -----(+6) ------ H<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>$----(+6) -----P -----(+6) ------ 7&nbsp; -----(+6) ------ Q<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Therefore, ? = TU7<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6546","question":"<p>In which shift do three of them work?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"I","option2":"II","option3":"III","option4":"I or III","option5":"Data inadequate","correct_option":"I","qa_date":"2016-06-07 06:48:52","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>P, R, and Z work in Shift l.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6525","question":"<p>Amar started a business investing Rs. 45,000. Six months later Prakash joined him with Rs. 30,000. In what ratio should the profit they earn be distributed at the end of the year?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"3 : 1","option2":"3 : 4","option3":"3 : 2","option4":"Data inadequate","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"3 : 1","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:38:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Ratio of equivalent capitals of Amar and Prakash for 1 month<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">= 45000 &times; 12 : 30000 &times; 6<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">=540000 : 180000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">= 3 : 1<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">So, Ratio of profit sharing = 3 : 1<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6531","question":"<p>The wheat sold by a grocer contained 10% low quality wheat. What quantity of good quality wheat should be added to 150 kgs of wheat so that the percentage of low quality wheat becomes 5%?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"150 kgs","option2":"135 kgs","option3":"50 kgs","option4":"85 kgs","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"150 kgs","qa_date":"2016-06-06 07:54:39","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">Good quality content in 150kgs of wheat = 90% 150<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">= 135 kg<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">In new mixture, low quality wheat is 5%. So good quality wheat 95%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">5%&nbsp; of new mixture&nbsp;= 15 kg<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">New mixture<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">=&nbsp;<span style=\"font-size:14px\"><sup>15&times;100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>5<\/sub>&nbsp;<\/span>= 300 kg<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">Good quality of wheat added<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:72pt\">=(300 &ndash; 150) kg. = 150 kg.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6533","question":"<p>A water tank has three taps A,B and C. Tap A, when opened , can fill the water tank alone in 4 hours. Tap B, when opened, can fill the water tank alone in 6 hours and tap C, when opened ,can empty the water tank alone in 3 hours . If taps A,B and C are opened simultaneously how long will it take to fill the tank completely?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"10 hours ","option2":"8 hours ","option3":"18 hours","option4":"12 hours","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"12 hours","qa_date":"2016-06-06 08:03:55","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Part of the tank filled in 1 hour when all the taps are opened<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4<\/sub>&nbsp;+&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>6<\/sub>&nbsp;-&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>3<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>3+2-4<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>12<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>12<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Hence, the tank will be filled in 12 hours.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6552","question":"<p><strong>Statements : <\/strong>S&nbsp; $&nbsp; T,&nbsp; T&nbsp; @&nbsp; R,&nbsp; R&nbsp; #&nbsp; M<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I<\/strong>. B&nbsp; @&nbsp; K<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;II.<\/strong> M &copy; T<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"1","qa_date":"2016-06-07 07:38:34","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><strong>Statements: &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>S&nbsp; $&nbsp; T,&nbsp; T&nbsp; @&nbsp; R,&nbsp; R&nbsp; #&nbsp; M<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>After&nbsp; conversion <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>S&nbsp; &ge;&nbsp; T,&nbsp; T&nbsp; &le;&nbsp; R,&nbsp; R &lt;&nbsp; M<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Or,&nbsp; S&nbsp; &ge;&nbsp; T&nbsp; &le;&nbsp; R&nbsp; &lt;&nbsp; M<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions <\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-roman\">\r\n\t<li>M&nbsp; &times;&nbsp; T&nbsp; &rarr;&nbsp; M&nbsp; &gt;&nbsp; T&nbsp; :&nbsp; true<\/li>\r\n\t<li>M&nbsp; &copy;&nbsp; T&nbsp; &rarr;&nbsp; M&nbsp; =&nbsp; T :&nbsp; not true<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n"},{"id":"6562","question":"<p>If all the people are asked to stand in and alphabetical order from left to right, the positions of how many will remain unchanged?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"One ","option2":"Two","option3":"Three","option4":"None","option5":"None of these           ","correct_option":"One ","qa_date":"2016-06-07 08:13:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6518","question":"<p>In an examination it is required to get 65% of the aggregate marks to pass a student gets 540 marks and is declared failed by 5%. What are the maximum aggregate marks a student can get?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"900","option2":"860","option3":"750","option4":"Cannot be determined         ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"900","qa_date":"2016-06-02 09:28:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>60% marks = 540<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>100% marks = <sup>540&times;100<\/sup>\/<sub>60 <\/sub>= 900<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6550","question":"<p>In which shift does V work?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"II","option2":"III","option3":"ll or lll","option4":"Data inadequate ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"III","qa_date":"2016-06-07 06:48:52","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>V works in Shift lll.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6560","question":"<p>Who is standing second to the right of C?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"F","option2":"D","option3":"G","option4":"E","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"G","qa_date":"2016-06-07 08:13:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>G is standing second to the right of C.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6499","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word from the given options.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"important  ","option2":"juvenile ","option3":"insignificant","option4":"supreme ","option5":"part","correct_option":"important  ","qa_date":"2016-06-02 05:35:31","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""}]